The new morning we've finally found
やっと見つけた　新しい朝は
Yatto mitsuketa atarashii asa wa
is being hampered by the past.
月日が邪魔をする
Tsukihi ga jama wo suru
What we chased after wasn't the future,
向かう先は　「次」じゃなくて
Mukau saki wa tsugi ja nakute
but the past so full of remorse.
「過」ばかり追いかけた
Sugi bakari oikaketa
The ruthless memories won't stop playing;
鳴り止まない　容赦ない思い出たちは
Nariyamanai yousha nai omoide tachi wa
they won't be forgiving us for a long time.
許してくれそうにもない
Yurushite kuresou nimonai
It's about now that a teardrop
そろそろかな　手探り　疲れた頬を
Sorosoro kana tesaguri tsukareta hoho wo
beings to roll down my fatigued cheeks.
葛藤がこぼれ落ちる
Kattou ga koboreochiru
Will this rain ever stop?
雨は　いつか止むのでしょうか
Ame wa itsuka yamunodeshouka
I've been freezing for a long time.
ずいぶん長い間　冷たい
Zuibun nagai aida tsumetai
Why does the rain continue to fix on me?
雨は　どうして僕を選ぶの
Ame wa doushite boku wo erabuno
I wonder if it could embrace me.
包まれて　いいかな
Tsutsumarete iikana
Today, the rain falls again;
雨は　止むことを知らずに
Ame wa yamu koto wo shirazuni
endlessly it falls knowing no end.
今日も降り続くけれど
Kyou mo furitsuzukukeredo
We nestle close to each other to share the warmth
そっと　差し出した傘の中で
Sotto sashidashita kasa no naka de
under this umbrella, you gently held out to me.
温もりに　寄り添いながら
Nukumori ni yorisoinagara
A philosopher's stone!
賢者の石
Where did he get that?!
どこでそんなものを…
Smoke screening again?
また目くらましか
Like I'll fall for that again!
同じ手はくいません
A flash bang?!
閃光弾
That one was a decoy!
おとりだよ
Nothing less to be expected from the power of a philosopher's stone.
さすがは賢者の石
One transmutation after another...!
次から次へと　よくも
You...!
The power of a philosopher's stone never ceases to amaze me.
まったく賢者の石の力は見事なものです
I've used it before, so I know.
私も使ったことがあるので
よく分かりますよ
And that's why I'm confused about something.
それゆえ　分からない
Why don't you use that power to get your body back?
なぜその力を自分の体を取り戻すために
使わないのですか
Since you have the stone, it'll be easy to run from us.
石があれば  私たちから
逃げることなどはたやすい
Once you get away, you can use the power to get you and your brother's bodies back.
逃げきったなら　石を使い
二人で元の体に戻る
And doesn't that conclude your journey?
それであなたたちの旅は
終わりではないのですか
If we did that, we wouldn't be able to save everyone.
それだと　みんなを救えない
It's to fulfill your dearest wish.
悲願を達成するためです
In order to gain something, one must sacrifice.
何かを得るためには
何かを切り捨てねばならない
Hey,
あのさぁ
why are you saying there are only two options?
なんで　二択なの
Getting our bodies back, or saving everyone.
「元の体に戻る」のと
「みんなを救う」の
It's strange to think that only one of those can be granted.
どっちか一つしか選べないなんて変だろ
Why don't you consider the possibility of getting our bodies back, and at the same time, saving everyone?
なんで 「元の体を取り戻して
かつみんなを救う」が
選択肢にないんだよ
What about the law of equivalent exchange?
等価交換の法則は
I think that in order for humanity to progress, we must seek a possibility without being bound by principles.
原則に縛られずに
可能性を求めることも
人類の進歩には必要だと思うよ
I see.
なるほど
If that comes true, it'll be recognized by the world as a new principle.
それが実現すれば  新たな理として
この世に認められる
Right?
ということですね
Then you should prepare another possibility.
ならば　もう一つの可能性
The possibility of the two of you not getting your bodies back, and not being able to save anyone either.
「あなた方は戻れず
みんなも救えない」という選択肢も
用意しなさい
There's more on the way!
まだまだ
Okay! We can at least pierce his skin!
よし　皮膚の下はいける
That hurt...
痛ぇ
I'm gonna die...
死ぬ　めんどくせぇ
This is such a drag...
Dying is such a drag...
死ぬのも　めんどくせぇ
Such a drag...
めんどくせぇ
It's going to be such a drag...
超めんどくせぇよ　本気出すの
...to have to go all out...
何っ
What?!
Major General Armstrong!
アームストロング少将
武器を捨てろ
Put down your weapons!
What the hell is that giant?!
なんだ　あのでかいのは
That was...!
今のは…
Yeah.
I... missed...
外…れた
W-What speed...!
なっ　なんというスピード…
Sloth the Lazy.
怠惰のスロウス
Sister!
姉上
Just barely grazed.
少し引っ掛けた
Did you see that?
今の  見えたか
Only slightly.
かすかにしか
Moving at that speed while weighing so much...
この重量でこのスピードとは…
It's almost unfair.
いやはや　反則だな
Yeah, I'm...
そう　オレ　最速の人造人間
...the fastest Homunculus.
Alex!
アレックス
I think... he's so fast that he can't even control his direction.
こいつ　速すぎて　自分でも
コントロールが利かないんじゃ…
Shit-
しまっ…
Finally... I hit.
やっと　当たった
What a beautiful sound.
いい音だ
The clashing of strong wills produces the most beautiful of sounds.
強い意志のぶつかり合いとは
かくも美しき音を奏でるものか
Alphonse Elric is still nearby.
アルフォンス·エルリックは
まだ近くにいますね
I'm sure of it.
そうでしょうとも
He won't die that easy.
これしきで死ぬわけがない
Right there!
そこ
That again? How unexciting.
また目くらましとは芸がない
It's futile.
無駄です
I told you, I can sense where you are by smell.
においで
居場所は分かると言ったでしょう
Checkmate.
チェックメイトです
I wouldn't be so sure.
どうかな  ここからが
This is where the tenacity of humans comes in!
人間のしぶといところさ
Even if you have a philosopher's stone,
賢者の石があっても
たった一人で我々に勝てるわけ…
there's no way you can beat us on your own-
一人じゃない
I'm not on my own!
Where did you hide the stone?!
石をどこへ
It couldn't be...
まさか…
The motive behind this cloud of dust is...
この土煙の目的は
...to know the direction of the wind?
風向きを知るため
He must have something up his sleeve within the leeward where my sense of smell is useless...
私の嗅覚の利かない風下で
何か細工を…
Behind me?!
後ろから…
It can't be...!
バカな…
How can he move with that wound...?!
あの傷でなぜ動ける…
Doctor Marcoh!
ドクター·マルコー
アイスクリーム屋の
An ice cream truck, right?
トラックだったよな
Yeah. Don't miss it.
見逃すなよ
Right.
錬金術って　本当に便利ですよね
Alchemy is so useful, isn't it?
車の外装を変えることなど
It's a simple matter to change the appearance of a motor vehicle.
造作もないよ
ここもダメですね
We can't go in through here either.
東西南北　司令部すべての門が
All the gates that allow entry into the Central Headquarters have been sealed off.
閉鎖されています
どうします　強行突破しますか
What should we do?
Force our way through?
No, leave the rough jobs up to the Briggs soldiers.
いや　表の荒っぽいことは
ブリッグズのヤツらに任せてしまえ
我々は裏のルートを使おう
We'll use an underground route.
はい
Roger.
ここからは別行動だ
We're going to split up now.
君らは夫人を伴い
I want you all to accompany the madam and head to the location.
例の場所へ向かってくれ
了解
Roger.
肉厚で助かった
Good thing I'm meaty.
痛い…
さすがは賢者の石といったところか
Can't underestimate the power of a philosopher's stone, I guess.
足だ　足を狙え
Their legs!
Aim for their legs!
なんだ
What?!
アレックス
Alex!
何　ただの脱臼です
Just a minor dislocated joint.
姉上は
What about you, Sister?
ただの骨折だ
Just a broken bone or two.
姉上
Sister!
さっさと殺して　寝る
I want to hurry up and kill you...
...so I can nap.
止めた
He stopped?!
キンブリーを刺すのをためらった
He's hesitant to stab Kimblee?
でも　こいつがそんなこと…
But why would someone like him...
なるほど
I see now.
君の言うとおり人間はしぶとい　しかし
Just as you said, humans are tenacious.
However, you all won't be able to beat us.
君たちは勝てないのです
あそこに  我らの父上がいるかぎりね
As long as...
...our father is seated right over there.
もっとも  それ以前に君たちは
Well, before that, you all need to find a way to get out of this situation.
この状況をどうにかしないと
いけないわけですけど
誰
Who?!
やってやったぞ…
I did it...
やってやったぞ
I sure did it!
ヨキ
Yoki?!
よっしゃ　いいぞ　チョロひげ
Nice one, mustache man!
まさか　君が来てくれるとは
I didn't expect you  to show up!
お前らばっかに
I can't let you guys have all the spotlight!
カッコつけさせてたまるかよ
私にもカッコつけさせろ  ちくしょ
Let me show off too, geez!
どうだ　このヨキ様が
Did you see that?!
I, Yoki, gave the strongest Homunculus a good beatdown!
最強の人造人間に
一発かましてやった
You saw it!
かましてやったんだぞ
どうした　この車
Where did you get this car?!
キンブリーが乗ってきたやつだよ
It's the one Kimblee rode here in.
運転してた人には少し休んでもらってる
I'm having the drivers take a little break.
やるなぁ　マルコー先生
Not bad, Doctor Marcoh.
出せ　出せ
Step on it!
黙って走れ　全力で走れ
Shut up and drive!
Drive as fast as you can!
あの化け物と
I don't plan on fighting that monster head-on again!
正面切って戦う気はねぇ
セントラル市内へ行け
Drive to Central!
あれに追いつかれる前に
We need to meet up with Ed and the others and defeat Father before that thing catches up with us!
エドたちと合流して
お父様とやらをつぶす
勇気ある逃げない人間というのは
Brave humans sure are easy to trick.
本当にのせやすい
よかった　まだ生きてますね
Oh good, you're still alive.
いい色のスーツに
I like the new color of your suit, Kimblee.
なったじゃないですか　キンブリー
百獣の王とはよくいったものです
Now I know why they call lions the "king of beasts".
弱肉強食の掟に従って
Obeying the rule of "survival of the fittest",
あっさりと君ののど笛を
he gouged out your throat.
かみきってしまいました
やはり人間はこの世界において
I guess humans really are of no importance to this world.
取るに足らない存在なのですね
君　世界が何を選ぶのか見てみたいと
You were saying something about wanting to see what option this world would choose, right?
常々言っていましたね
それなのに　こんなところで滅ぶなんて
It would be a disgrace if you were to just die here like this.
さぞや　屈辱でしょう
でも　心配しないで
But don't worry.
君は私の中で生き続けるのだから
You're going to continue to live inside me.
何が…どうなった…
What... happened...?
アレックス
Alex!
勝手に突っ込んでくるのですから
Since he rushes at you on his own, all you have to do is wait for him.
待ち構えていればよいのです
姉上　立てますか
Can you stand, Sister?
そういえば
Now that I recall, a shoot-on-sight order has been issued for me.
私に銃殺命令が出ていたな
なんと　それは困ります
What?!
That won't do!
アームストロング家は
I'm going to inherit the Armstrong household,
我が輩が継ぐのですから
手続きをしてから
so I can't have you die until you complete the formalities!
死んでいただかないと
無用な心配だ　私が死んだら
You don't need to worry about that.
I've made it so that the mansion will go to Mustang if I were to die.
屋敷はマスタングにくれてやることになっている
そのような約束を家族に相談もなく…
You made a promise like that without even discussing it with your family?!
貴様のようなヘタレより
He's better than a failure like you by a hair.
ヤツの方がまだミジンコ１匹分はマシだ
それが助けに来た者への態度ですか
Is that how you're supposed to treat someone who came to your rescue?!
なんだ　これ
What's... going on?
敵襲か
Enemy raid?
まさか　マスタング隊
Don't tell me... it's Mustang's squad?!
なっ　なんじゃ　こりゃ
W-What the hell?!
う…撃っても死なないぞ
Shooting them doesn't do a thing!
ブリッグズの兵か
Are they soldiers from Briggs?!
どあほ　うちの屈強なヤツらと
Moron!
Don't confuse my burly men with those scrawny blue monsters!
あんな青っちろいガリガリを一緒にするな
おそらく　これと同類だ
They're probably the same kind of thing as this is.
貴様らに命令を出しているヤツが
The one who commanded you fools is probably behind it.
動かしているんだろう
我々はそのようなことを
We were never told of this!
知らされていない
貴様らは知らなくとも
I don't think they care whether or not you were told.
向こうさんはお構いなしのようだが
どうする　我ら姉弟なら
What will you do?
Us siblings can fight those monsters.
こいつら化け物に対処できるぞ
しかし…
But...
さあ　どうする
So, what will you do?!
我らを撃ち殺して
Are you going to kill us and end up being eaten by monsters,
後に化け物の餌食になるか
それとも　我らと協力して化け物を討つか
or will you cooperate with us to destroy those fiends?!
自分の頭で考えろ
Learn to think for yourself!
この
You!
またです
Again?!
ムダだよ
It's no use.
こいつら　賢者の石を注入された
They're soldier dolls that were injected with philosopher's stones.
人形兵だからねぇ
ちょっとやそっとじゃ死なないよ
It'll take more than that to kill them!
ほらほら
See? Look at that.
逃げてばっかりいるから…
また吸収して
I got stronger by absorbing them because you keep dodging my attacks.
強くなっちゃったじゃないかよ
分かってませんね
You don't get it at all.
その人形に大群で来られると
It would be troublesome if those dolls were to all rush at me,
厄介ですけど
あなた一人なら
but it's simple as pie to run away if it's only you chasing me!
逃げるのもたやすい
ほざけ
Bullshit!
この人形は賢者の石を注入されている
These dolls have been injected with philosopher's stones.
だから死なない
That's why they won't die.
やはり　不老不死は賢者の石に…
So the secret to immortality really is in those stones...?
部族を救うためです
It's to save my clan!
不老不死を我が手に
I need to obtain the secret to immortality!
It hurts...
痛い…
痛いよ…
Pain...
まだ出てくんのかよ
There's still  more of them?!
キリがねぇ
There's no end to them!
針が尽きそうだ
I'm almost out of stings!
こっちも　唾液がかれてきた
I'm just about out of saliva as well.
くそっ
Dammit!
しまった
Shit!
エド
Ed!
君のいる場所はいつも騒々しいな
It's always so unruly wherever I find you.
手を貸した方がよいかね
Shall I lend you a hand,
鋼の
Fullmetal?
Ever since that day passed,
あの日からずっと
Ano hi kara zutto
I promised myself that I'd never cry.
泣かないと決めてきたけど
Nakanaito kimetekitakedo
But even while I hoarded up the pain,
痛みを重ねても
Itami wo kasanetemo
there was something I couldn't forgive myself for.
何かを許せずにいた
Nanika wo yurusezu ni ita
I'll never be able
もう戻れない
Mou modorenai
to return to those days.
いくつもの日々
Ikutsumo no hibi
I'm still powerless.
僕はまだ何もできずに
Boku wa mada nanimo dekizuni
I watch as the shards of memories disappear, one by one;
君のいた記憶の破片
Kimi no ita kioku no kakera
memories of when you were still with me.
またひとつ 消えてゆく
Mata hitotsu kieteyuku
I long to become
今日よりもっと
Kyou yori motto
stronger than I am now,
強くなりたい
Tsuyoku naritai
so that my voice will eventually reach you.
この声がいつか届くように
Kono koe ga itsuka todokuyouni
If the wind happens to stop
歩き続けて
Arukitsuzukete
in the midst of my long journey,
風が止んだら
Kaze ga yandara
I'll look up at the sky in search of you.
君を探して空見上げるよ
Kimi wo sagashite sora miageruyo
Beyond the daybreak, a ray of light breaks free.
夜明けの先に光がさすよ
Yoake no saki ni hikari ga sasuyo
A rainbow spans across the sky.
虹がかかるよ
Niji ga kakaruyo
次回　鋼の錬金術師
日本語字幕仕上げ：XIAOBIN
When people arrive at the truth,
Fullmetal  Alchemist
they lay their hearts bare.
第５３話　『復習の炎』
漫遊字幕組
http://popgo.net/bbs
They are unable to stop themselves, nor do they have the luxury of choice.
焼き尽くせ　すべてを
Next time, Fullmetal Alchemist:
Episode 53, Flame of Vengeance.
Reduce everything to ashes.